Christopher Aubert

Website: www.chrisaubert.co.uk Email: contactme@chrisaubert.co.uk Github: www.github.com/GeekyAubergine

Second year Computer Science student with experience in Web Development and Game Development. Proficient in a large range of languages including Java and Python. I enjoy working in a team or independently, and can communicate effectively with both technical and non technically minded colleagues to achieve more appropriate solutions to problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Java	JavaScript	Python	HTML5	CSS3	PHP	SQL
Tools	Eclipse	Git	d3.js	Node.js	MySQL	Linux	Atom

DEGREE EDUCATION

2014 - Present : University of Portsmouth

Computer Science (BSc Hons), First year average: 78%

The course focuses on developing both theoretical and practical skills, developing transferable skills in:

- Independent Work and Time Management; working on multiple long term projects independently while effectively managing my workload and setting my own deadlines.
- **Teamwork and Leadership**; working within teams of up to 6 colleagues while also taking on some leadership roles within the teams.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

May 2014 - Present: Software Developer

Hautlieu School, Jersey

- Developed a program designed to test the logical thinking skills of young children as an individual project using Java and the LWJGL library.
- Developed a data extraction and collation program to compile the results of the tests into a more usable format, created using Python and the xlsxwriter library.
- Worked with teachers to design logical thinking problems, the problems were then tested by other students to determine their complexity.
- Worked with young children to aid in the testing procedure, this involved traveling to multiple schools aiding in the setup of the equipment and software, and overseeing the running of the tests.
- Provide regular maintenance and development to the applications as the needs change.

Oct 2014 - Present : Software and Web Developer

UPRacing - University of Portsmouth Formula Student Team

- Took responsibility for the team website and telemetry system.
- Redesigned and rebuilt the team website. Included viewing competitor websites and taking inspiration from features that would fit our needs. Built using PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Built a telemetry system that worked on both mobile and other devices using Node.js as a server running on a Raspberry Pi/Odroid C1.
- Designed and implemented data visualisation as requested by other members of the team, this was done using the d3.js library.
- Trained others in both the use and maintenance of the systems. Writing explanatory documentation and delivering face to face training.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

SortingVisualiser

An application that is designed to be embedded in a website to allow the user to understand the way in which a sorting algorithm behaves in a graphical way. This project was built using JavaScript, d3.js, jQuery and CSS.

AstroAssault

Developed a game for iOS using the Cocos2d and Box2d libraries written in Objective-C. Worked with game designers, artists and musicians. This project was launched to the AppStore in 2013 and remained available for approximately 18 months.

Java Libraries

Produced a large open source Java library for both general utilities such as logging and file handling (GeekyJUtil) and mathematical functions (GeekyJMath).

INTERESTS

Music

Achieved grade 7 in Trumpet, developing skills such as working in teams, self discipline and time management.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

2010 - 2014 : Hautlieu School, Jersey

- A-Levels: Maths (E), Music (E), Physics (D)
- AS-Level: Computing (C)
- GCSEs: 10 with Grades A-C including Maths, English and Triple Award Science

References available upon request